What I discovered is Elite Hoops during
basketball season, the beginning of
October to like the end of March, like
that's when I'll make 80% of the
revenue, give or take. And what I
discovered is it's getting so much on
its own. Apple search ads do really,
really well for it. I wish I could even
spend more. Like I up the spend on it
all the time, and I've hit the ceiling
of like what people search for in a day,
and I'm pretty confident I capture most
of that. Welcome to Launched. I'm
Charlie Chapman and this is the annual
Christmas special with the one and only
Jordan Morgan.
>> Jordan,
>> hello. Hello.
>> Welcome back.
>> It's that time of year.
>> Yes, this is uh this is becoming one of
my favorite traditions. So, for those of
you who don't know, uh, every year since
I started this podcast, I think so it's
been like four or five years, uh, we've
done a Christmas special where we get
together and a normal episode of
launched, as you hopefully know, is I'm
interviewing somebody about a new app or
something that they've released and kind
of the story behind it. And this episode
is uh is basically my chance to naval
gaze with one of my best indie app
friends uh Jordan who we've sort of had
these I don't want to say parallel indie
lives but they've been crisscrossing.
You you were doing this longer than me.
You released an app before me and then
you got out of the app game and you
became an author for a while and so this
is our chance to sort of talk about our
feelings for for an hour and hang out.
>> It's therapeutic. Yeah. Yeah. So yeah,
lots lots of overlap. I mean, everyone
in southwest Missouri is just waiting to
hear the indie dev tales between us. So,
we gota get
>> That's another piece of of lore here is
that uh we are both from Missouri in the
United States. Uh which this might
surprise anybody who knows a lot about
Missouri, but it's not the land filled
with indie iOS developers. Uh, we like
to joke that there's a rule, unwritten
rule here, that you're only allowed to
have one indie app developer per major
city because we have like a little group
of us, but there's literally only one of
us in each in each city. It feels like
>> it's true. Yeah, there's there's not
very many. Um, and that hasn't changed
in the five years we've been doing this.
>> Well, we've had some move out. Uh, yeah,
Colombia, I think, still is looking for
one. Uh, I don't know of any there right
now. No, no, they're we're we're sparse.
>> I figured it's been long enough and
hopefully now that this podcast has been
rebirthed as a Revenue Cat podcast,
hopefully there's a there's a new
audience maybe who doesn't already know
our full backstory. If you don't, I'd
recommend just go through the the back
catalog and well, really, you should
just listen to every episode of Launch.
set aside a Tinder 5 hours and you're
>> Yeah, you should go through find all the
Christmas specials and listen to them.
Actually, it's become kind of a
tradition of mine to listen to our
previous episodes, which is always very
fascinating.
>> It's like a weird weird way to reflect
on your year, to listen to yourself from
past years, recollect that year.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's kind of funny. If you
don't already know our story, I wanted
to give just a quick recap of how we got
to where we are and then we can kind of
jump into the last year's, you know,
things that we've been trying and and
how we're feeling on those. It was right
after I launched my indie app, Dark
Noise, White Noise app. And right
before, like a month or two before I
launched my app was when you launched
Spinstack, which was your indie app that
you had been working on for
>> a very long time.
>> Yeah. much longer than I had been
working on dark noise. But since that
time, uh, you have s you sold spinsack.
So that was sold. Then you have
reacquired the the opensource rights to
spinstack. I I don't remember how that
went.
>> I have the whole app now. Yeah, that was
this year. Like I it's back in my app
Apple developer.
>> Oh, that was this year.
>> Yeah, I I think it was this year. They
gave me open source rights to it I think
last year and then this year I was like,
"Hey, can I just have it back?" And
they're like, "Yeah, sure." So yeah,
it's back in my developer account.
>> Maybe we can get into that because
that's a whole interesting thing is a
very long uh recollection of selling
your selling your baby in a way in in
that case for you.
>> They gave it back for free. So Bad Baby.
>> Yeah.
Yes. Exactly. If we did uh episode
titles, that would be the title of the
episode. Bad baby. So after you sold
your app though, you didn't immediately
jump back into the indie app developer
game. you became a an author. So, you
wrote the best-in-class iOS app book
series which
>> took a few years off of your life uh
both literally and in the color of your
hair probably. Now, it's an achievement.
You have this big book and you keep that
updated over time.
>> I've released a couple little little
apps. Uh none of them were major big
deals. I had a app that was free for
teachers that, you know, got some press
coverage and stuff, but it wasn't it
wasn't even paid, so it wasn't a big
one. And then I switched over from a
paid upfront app to subscriptions and
then very quickly after that joined
revenue where I talk about doing that
you know all day long. And then you
actually before you you also joined me
in the sort of developer advocate game.
You also jumped back into the indie app
developer game with elite hoops, right?
That was before you switch jobs. And can
you remind us uh like what the main
pitch is for elite hoops? Yeah, it's
just I call it a toolkit for basketball
coaches. You can share plays, run
practices, and save drills. Those are
like the main core tent poles of it.
>> Yeah. Aimed at basketball coaches
specifically, like not players.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. We talked a lot about that in
previous Christmas specials. And then
both of us have released Vision Pro
versions of that app. Probably won't
talk about that here, but that was a
thing that happened. You joined
Superwall, uh, a great partner of
Revenue. Is Is that the corporate by
line before the show?
>> It's not a cor No, no, no. I I love
Superwall. I like Jake. I like Brian. I
like the whole team. Super wall is
great.
>> I was trying to think of some good like
burns to give the internet some drama,
but I don't know. I didn't have time. I
do wonder how many people who watch our
companies online will think that this is
like a I can't believe they're together.
Nature is healing. Look at them.
>> Nature's healing. Yeah. No, me and
Jordan, we go way back. But also, the
Superwall team's great. Like uh
>> we have a good relationship. I feel
like. But yeah. So now you're a
developer advocate. I'm a developer
advocate. We both have uh sort of side
apps on the side. And then over the last
year, we've actually both released new
apps, which I do want to get into, but
first I want to catch up on like what
the latest is with Elite Hoops. The last
episode, I was just listening to it.
>> You talked a lot about uh your like paid
advertising that you've been doing with
that. Yeah.
>> And you were like, we'll we'll check in
next year to see how that's gone. cuz
>> you had recently kind of been ramping it
up and so I guess now I get to ask you
how has that gone?
>> That's actually a really good uh thing
to talk about cuz I have like a lot of
new news there. So yeah, at Tri Swift my
talk there I mentioned paid ads as well
and like the ironic funny thing about
that is I've never been doing paid ads
right or correctly.
>> I think I said that to you a lot during
this episode. Everyone I talked to that
does actual marketing has has has told
me that. So like you know when they ask
like hey what's your uh you know CPI?
What's it cost? What's your LTV cost to
acquire customer? All these things. I'm
like well actually I don't even have
like the Facebook SDK installed. So like
I just kind of know like what my
installs normally look like when I turn
ads off and on. And some like there's
two reactions. Some of them are like
nice like oh you know okay I get it.
Like I know what you mean. And other
people are like dude you are what are
you doing? Like you're wasting money.
like you have to be able to like know
what's working. So, I think uh cuz you
know I'm pretty transparent with the
numbers. I think this year I've spent
16k on ads. I only spent $30 a day right
now because two reasons. One, I hired a
marketing agency this past month to show
me like how to do this, right? Yeah. To
like teach me how to actually do paid
ads correctly. And two, what I
discovered is elite hoops during
basketball season, cuz it's like 90% of
the paid user bases, they're American,
probably higher than that, probably like
95.
>> Over the few years it's been out, I know
it's seasonal. So like the beginning of
October to like the end of March, like
that's when I'll make 80% of the
revenue. Like give or take that if I had
to guess off the top of my head, I'll
make most of the revenue in these next,
you know, four or five months. And what
I discovered is it's just it's getting
so much on its own. Um, Apple search ads
do really really well for it. I wish I
could even spend more. Like I up the
spend on it all the time and I've kind
of hit the ceiling of like, you know,
what people search for uh in a day and
I'm pretty confident I capture most of
that.
>> You're saying Apple search ads are doing
well. Do you know that now? Like are you
looking at your cost of acquisition and
your LTV? And is the math mathing?
>> The math is mathing. And this is where I
have to put the the big ironic asterisk.
So yes, I started this app 2023 before I
joined Superwall. So like my uh app
doing really well is on Revenue Cat,
which I always, you know, h have to
laugh at the the irony. But I do tell
people like I want apps on every
platform because I want to know like
what the pain points are, how things
Yeah. So I have apps on RevenueCat, on
Superwall, with the mix with neither
one. When you guys first launched like
the Apple search ads attribution thing,
I turned that on like the day that I saw
your video about it. So yeah, like I can
go and look in the charts and see like
where actual paid conversions are coming
from and segment it by like the Apple
search ads stuff. So yeah, I can see
that that does really well, but it caps
like 500 bucks a week. Like that's the
most I can spend on it. Like I would
spend more if I could.
>> That's a limit like Apple just has for
everybody.
>> No, no, no. It's just like that's the
search volume. So yeah, but I don't know
how much you want to dive into paid ads
at at the moment, but the preview is
from my learnings with the marketing
agency is I think the term they said was
like, "Turn that off right now. You're
burning money.
>> Turn off Apple search ads.
>> Turn off the ads that I've made on my
own, like the way that I have it."
They're like, "Turn that off right now.
The money that you're making right now
is not because of this basically is what
they were saying. Like you're just
you're making money because it's in
season. your search, you have good ASO
for it. Your Apple search ads are
working like this. This is not making a
difference what the setup that you have
current.
>> So they're saying to turn off your
non-Apple search ads.
>> Correct. My meta ads. Yeah.
>> So the meta ads specifically. Yeah.
Yeah. Gotcha.
>> Yeah. That the ads as I have them today
are pointless basically is is kind of
what they're saying. The biggest reason
they gave is like one they're like yes
you need attribution. Like you have to
figure out how to do it. And I think I
may have even put this like in our group
chat. I was like, you you either die the
righteous India or live long enough to
have to finally install the Facebook SDK
or something like that, you know? So,
like the biggest reason they said is
like, so I made one and this might have
been this year, so we may not even
talked about it. I I can't remember if
we chatted about it last year, but I
made one video that went semiviral and
hit like I don't know, say like 200,000
organic views and then I pumped ad spin
behind it. And whether it's correlation
or causation, you know, because I don't
have the SDK, revenue like did super
well in that time for me. And I and I'm
pretty confident that's where it came
from.
>> Yeah.
>> But what the marketing agents and
they're called uh EVO uh consulting,
EVO, they're they're great bunch. Just
finished up with them. Le learned a ton
that I'm sure we'll chat about. But they
were pretty much saying like you're just
milking the same creative like you've
been using the same creative like all
year. It's that's not going to work.
like you need you need to refresh their
creatives and you need to do that fairly
often. So this one that you have like
it's done, you know, like it it served
its purpose.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, it's time to move on and you
got to use something else. So yeah,
that's that's kind of what they gave me.
But uh yeah, so TLDDR, I'm a big
believer in paid ads. I've used them a
lot. I've spent a lot of money on them
and now I know kind of how to do them
correctly cuz I never have had the setup
exactly how it's supposed to be. So, you
do have that set up now?
>> That's next on the list. So, I what I
have right now from the marketing agency
are how to correctly run a paid ads
campaign. Like, they taught me how that
looks. I have to get the Facebook SDK
installed. Um, which that doesn't take
long. So, that's like my next technical
thing I have to do before I I turn these
on. And as part of the consulting
package, I have 20 creatives to use,
which to me was the biggest value ad
because
>> I don't like making creatives. Um, it's
like I just don't like it, you know? So,
I have like a very good game plan, a
professional that knows what they're
doing, set everything up for me, they
gave me the playbook, now I just have to
kind of execute on it is is where it's
at.
>> And your idea is that you're going to do
your own creatives and then run them as
ads basically. This isn't using
influencers.
>> This is using their creatives. So, yeah.
So, the videos themselves, there's
different formats, but they made them
all for me. So, like they have like
their own creators that they contract
with. And the thing that really
impressed me is like the first thing
that they did is they came up with this
massive like notion doc of like who my
ICP is like my ideal customer persona
what the strengths of elite elite hoops
are why people would download it how to
talk about it and it was almost surreal
seeing that cuz it's like this thing
that I've worked on for like two and a
half years like they knew it better than
me like I was like oh dude this makes
like so much sense like okay yeah like
this is how
>> from a very different angle than you
>> a pure marketing one. Yeah. And it just
like reinforced to me like how people
have that talent. They have that bone in
their body to kind of like dig through.
And if you told me like I had to make a
notion doc like that, like I would put
it off for months cuz it just sounds
like that kind of thing is so mentally
taxing to me. Like okay, my ideal
customer persona.
>> That's what chat GPT is for.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Chat it up.
>> I don't know they would do a good job.
Although it's a good way to get started.
>> It is a good way to get started. But uh
so yeah, so what they've delivered to me
is basically a lot of information on how
to market elite hoops, the people that
I'm trying to reach, how I should talk
to those people, and most importantly,
how to correctly set up a ad campaign
with Meta, and here's a good starting
point of creatives you can use to to get
going on that. So really, I've had paid
ads and they've never been done
correctly, and I want to see what
happens when I do set them up correctly.
um because it does so well just with
Apple search ads and organic search
right now that like maybe this is the
that last little bit of gasoline I need
to kind of make it you know go to the
next step and and grow faster than it is
right now.
>> So I guess that gives us our uh you know
first follow-up item for for 2026
Christmas special.
>> Yeah. And you know it'll be like oh I
never installed the SDK you know I just
like hey I'll do it later.
>> Oh yeah that's gonna start next week. Uh
yeah. Oops.
>> What about over the last year though?
Like has it been growing? Like I know
the ad agency was saying the creatives
aren't the reason that it's doing
whatever it's doing, but has the needle
been moving basically?
>> Yeah. So the start of the year, this is
kind of what it's done the last two
year. Then it goes up and to the right
until about the end of March, beginning
of April, and then it'll stay basically
straight the whole way through until I
get back to October and then it'll go up
again. What are we saying goes up
though? Is that revenue or is that your
like MR or something?
>> You could pretty much say every healthy
business metric.
>> Like I get that it's seasonal in the
sense that that's when the money starts
coming in, but like is it growing,
flatlining, and then growing on top of
that or is it like goes up, goes down,
goes up, but then the baseline kind of
stays the same,
>> you know? Let's uh let's look at some
charts and find out, why don't we?
>> Yeah. No, it's it's grown every single
year. It's It's never kind of stayed
stagnant. So like AR is going climbing
climbing climbing till we get to about
May and then from May all the way to
September like it barely moves. It
doesn't really go up, doesn't really go
down, just kind of stays where it's at.
>> So you're not getting new subscribers at
that point?
>> No, not really. Not during that time,
which surprised me because I thought I
could really hit like the summer ball
circuit um like AAOU teams because
that's that's their time. And since, you
know, I ask people like their
demographics during onboarding,
a lot of them are AAU coaches. So, I
don't know if they've already subscribed
or what, but what the data is telling me
is it correlates to the basketball
season, which is not surprising, but I
am surprised it's I can't like kind of
hit that growth year round because
people are looking for a solution still
during the summertime. It is funny
because I'm looking at like I split it
out by 12 months and it looks like if
you started at the top right of the
graph, you'd be going down like the ski
slope and then you have like this nice
settling period where you know you can
kind of coast and then it goes down
again, you know. So like it's it's
weird. I I have this thing that seems to
kind of grow is in a spot where it's a
somewhat mature. It hasn't been out I
mean in the grand scheme of things very
long, but like I can I know when it's
going to start growing a bit more. But
your your churn once annuals started
hitting did not overcome the new
subscribers you you brought in.
>> It stayed straight. So, like during what
I call the off season, I'll get like one
or two conversions a day and then
because churn is depressing, I don't
ever look at it, you know, but obviously
what that chart is showing is like they
they pretty much cancel each other out,
you know, which is one reason why I have
the luxury, I guess, of being able to
like really try paid ads even more
because the revenue is is good for me
day in and day out now to where I know
it's going to make at least 500 to a
thousand pretty much every day. So, I
want to take that and and see I've never
been shy about just putting money back
into the business. Like, you know, what
would happen if I got to the point where
I could spend 500 a day on ads? Like,
what does it look like?
>> The description of us too is that yeah,
you will reinvest and I am 5 years in
still scared of the tax man suddenly
showing up. And so, it just
>> But you could buy like a Lamborghini in
and a mansion.
I could buy like a Mc McDonald's happy
value meal. So don't don't feel bad.
>> No, that's good though. Yeah, cuz like
my story is definitely different. Like
dark noise is coasting more or less.
It's not really going down like it goes
down some, you know, a big part of my
user acquisition is is press and Apple
features, right? So that's my big waves
anyway. So like September, October, I'll
get a lot from either Apple features
when a new version of iOS comes out or
mentions on podcasts, especially like
end of the year, like what's your
favorite, whatever, what apps are on
your home screen. Those always give me
some big spikes, but those those
subscribers I found I don't know the the
raw numbers, but at least based on the
shape of the graphs, it seems like those
tend to have a higher churn, which makes
sense cuz it's more people like
>> kicking the tires. they have disposable
income because they're the type of
people who listen to productivity apps,
but like they're not necessarily fully
invested. They weren't searching for it.
They heard about it on something. And so
that churn is higher. So depending on
how that year goes, some years, you
know, I'll lose more subscribers than I
gain because I had a really big year the
year before, not as big. Some years it
goes kind of the inverse, but more or
less it's like, but I haven't been
investing
heavily into Dark Noise like I would
like to be. It's more or less I'm
keeping it up to date every year with
the latest iOS features and it's kind of
plugging along. So, it's not like a
growing thing, but I did release a new
app which I listening to our last
episode, I actually talked about it. It
had a different name. It was called
Screen Frames initially, which was just
my like that I guess to back up. I had
decided I wanted to try just building an
app fast cuz I've I've always been like
you. I would sit there and just kind of
obsess over something for forever. And
I'm not a person who lets projects die
very often, but I will work on them for
a very long time before I release them.
And so I was like, I'm going to try
this. Yordy Bruin had this method called
the 222 method that was popular or maybe
still is popular where it's like
>> you work on something for two days and
get a working version and then you give
it two weeks and you should have a
version on test flight and then two
months you should have it out in the
store. Or maybe his is two hours, two
days, and two weeks. His is really
quick.
>> Very quick. It gave me anxiety. His like
>> Yeah. Yeah. But either way, I I made
mine a alternated version of that, but
it was the same thing where I was like,
"All right, I'm going to get a working
version as fast as I can." And I did. Uh
and and the idea that I had was I wanted
a Mac app that let me add device frames
around screenshots. So like app
developers, probably a lot of people
listening, you frequently use an Apple
shortcut or Figma or something where
it's like you take a screenshot of your
app in a certain phase and you want to
share it in some marketing asset. So you
need to put the frame of the phone
around it so it looks like it's in a
phone. And this was just to automate
that basically. And so I wanted I had a
very particular way I wanted it to work.
I wanted to be able to copy and paste
pictures into it and then copy and paste
pictures out of it and just do
everything immediately like that. And so
I built a really, really quick, really,
really dirty version that I never would
have even built it that way in the first
place. And then I got that version
cleaned up enough to get on test flight,
even where it was slow. Like it was very
slow because of architecturally the way
I did it was kind of insane. Like it was
literally I guess I This is the
Christmas special. We can go into stupid
details. The way I built it originally
was uh you know, you can rasterize a bit
map image out of a Swift UI view, right?
UI graphics render image renderer or
>> I don't remember how I don't remember
actually anymore. Yeah, it's going
through UI kit I think. But either way,
it's a Swift UI view. I'm rendering it
into an image.
>> But the screenshots are are decent sized
obviously. And then the frames that you
get them in are, you know, a decent
sized image. And so the way I built it
all originally was like I wanted you
need to be able to preview what the
image is going to look like. The way I
did it was I literally would render the
the bit map and then put that bit map in
the canvas. So like what you had in the
canvas was not Swift UI views being
rendered there. It was the bit map which
meant if you changed literally anything
it rerendered the whole image. And
that's fine. Like it was you know and
this is why I did it. It was like it was
fine. it got the job done. But like
especially as you, you know, if you had
a Mac screenshot, well that's, you know,
a 5K image depending on your screen and
then you have the ability to drag in
like three or four images to have, you
know, the phones lined up, which is
pretty popular, but that's a big image
even if you don't need it eventually
that big. Anyway, I I built that
version, got it on test flight really
fast. Um, and then, you know, life got
in the way. And so when we recorded last
year, I was in that phase where I had
released it the test flight, but I
hadn't gotten it fully released. Anyway,
this is a lot of context to say I did
release that app in I think March of
this year. It's now called Framus. Uh
which our our mutual friend Josh Holtz,
I just gave him my name and said, "You
need to give me a real name." That's
good. Although, here's a fun little
>> better than chat GPT at those names.
>> Yeah. Yes. And the best ones.
>> ChatGpt is bad at naming still.
>> Yeah. one thing it is just not good at.
But uh this is another fun little
tidbit. The And maybe you have an answer
for me here. Well, no you don't cuz I've
asked you this before
>> but uh the Mac App Store sucks. Did you
know this? Uh it's very bad.
>> Yeah, it's it's depressing every time I
go to it.
>> Yeah, but as a product it's very
frustrating. And and the reason I say
this is my app is called Framus. Like a
pun on Frame and Famous. And what I have
determined is that the Mac app store
just
autocorrects behind the scenes the word
famous into famous which means uh my app
never ranks to the top of the word
famous. It's always like fifth and it's
fifth behind like random apps but they
have the word you know famous whatever
and they have nothing to do obviously
with anything my app has to do with.
Would you like to give me a a live demo
of what you're behind right now when I
start famous?
>> Number So, you're you're seven. Okay,
this is great. Number one. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Art for you. Hyphen famous
paintings. Okay. Number two, famous
quotes. All right. Number three, famous
cities. Now, we're really going to go
off the rails on four four through six
here. Four, currency converter
calculator. Exclamation point. What's in
the subtitle? How did the word famous
exchange rate to USD
is the subtitle. And then this might be
my favorite. Number seven before famous
is Kingdom Rush HD. The most f Oh, there
we go. The most famous strategy TD.
Okay. So, of those currency calculator
has famous nowhere in it at all.
>> And to be clear, you searched like with
an R, right? I'm getting ready to send
you the screenshot.
>> Oh my gosh. Yeah. So, I thought I fixed
this. So, that, you know, the app came
out, did pretty well, got press in a lot
of, you know, the big podcast and stuff
and I was very excited and then I
noticed this problem and it's like I'm
doing all this earned press and so
people are going to the store and typing
in Framus and they don't see my app and
it's like this is insane. Like totally
insane. You know, I'm asking around and
everybody, all the the sort of usual
experts are like, to be fair, I don't
think most people know as much or care
as much about the Mac App Store. They're
like, "This doesn't seem right. I bet
it'll fix itself in a few days." And lo
and behold, in a few days, I was ranking
up at the top. And I thought, "Okay,
this is great." And I didn't pay much
attention to it for a while. And then I
go back, you know, a few months in and
I'm back down again. Like, what the
heck? And then after a couple more of
these like little press cycles, I
realized I'm pretty sure I'm just
ranking higher for the word famous
because
when I get a bunch of earned media, it's
like, oh yeah, lots of people are
downloading it here, but then it kind of
like falls back down. I don't know that
that's the case, but that's my only
guess because it does seem like when
there's a bunch of activity, it fixes
itself. And I thought it was like the
algorithm fixing itself or like some
engineer heard me complaining and uh you
know fixed whatever hard-coded not
probably not hardcoded but whatever
thing in there is making it say you know
they may have typed famous and we might
be showing that they typed famous but
let's just assume they actually meant
famous because that seems to be what's
happening. Very aggravating.
>> Just put famous in it but it looks like
you did that. So that was that was my
big amazing idea.
>> Well I have it in the subtitle, right? I
literally was thinking do I do the like
you you have it open. What do I I have
something in the title, right? It's like
screenshot sharing or screenshot frames
or something.
>> Yeah, let's see. It it says um frame
colon screenshot frames and then your
subtitle is famous device bezels framer
which I love. I love Yeah. I mean, you
just got to lean into it at that point.
>> Yeah. Very aggravating. But anyway, I
don't think that's a big deal because
it's not like my ASO on the word famous
matters. What it has to be hurting
though is it showing up on the app store
or uh somebody hearing about it on a
podcast or whatever, searching for it on
the app store and then it's like if you
don't see it in the top five result, the
top three results, that surely hurts the
amount of people
>> who actually convert. And even if you do
see it at that point, it makes it it's
below a bunch of apps that kind of give
you this vibe of like this doesn't seem
like, you know, very legitimate.
>> Yeah, I don't love it. But anyway, all
that to say, that app has been doing
>> really well for me actually. Like, it's
a meaningful amount. Like, it's a
noticeable bump.
>> Your SEO is fantastic. If you just type
Framus, it's the top top result on
Google. So, I mean, you got
>> And honestly, that's probably what more
people do on the Mac anyway. So, yeah,
that app has been doing pretty well. And
there's a couple interesting things I
did with that app that might be worth
talking about. I made it a subscription,
but then I kind of tried a slightly
different monetization method that I I
don't know yet if I've decided if I
regret it or not, but basically it's a
subscription for like $10 a year, or you
can you can do a lifetime purchase for
like 20 or something, but that lifetime
purchase only unlocks the frames that
came out in the year that you purchased
it and all the previous years. So, so
I'm selling the 2025
frames and anything that came up before.
Actually, I'm in the process right now.
The idea was I would run a Black Friday
sale and then after the Black Friday
sale is over, then I switch over and
I'll start selling the 2026 frames,
which is I'm literally like this weekend
is what I'll what I'll switch over to.
And so, it's it's annoying because it
means I I have to make sure I go in and
and do that. But, it's actually not too
complicated. And so, we'll see. Well,
I'll find out next year what that looks
like because if I if I convert,
you know, 30 or 40% of the people who
did that, which I probably won't, maybe
10% of the people, it might still even
out to being similar because it costs
more than the regular, you know, auto
renewing subscription would. So, it'll
be interesting to see how that goes.
>> I like that model cuz I remember uh I
don't know how I remember this. years
ago, Apple design award winner agenda.
They called it what? The cash cow, which
I think ironically, it was like an
ironic name, but like that was their
thing. Like if you bought I don't think
they actually had a subscription. Maybe
it was just like an inapp purchase or
non-consumable, but it's like if you
bought the date that you bought the tier
entitled you in perpetuity to the pro
stuff up to that date. But like if they
released another thing like after a year
or whatever then like you had to buy it
again or whatever with the idea being
like you never lost the pro features uh
features that you paid for which I
thought was interesting.
>> They were trying to do the sketch model
cuz like sketch at that time was really
popular with the whole you just get
updates up to a year after you bought it
or whatever.
>> But on the Mac that's like an easier
thing to do. But on on iPhones, it's
like you can't really do that because
you can't sell you can't like really
give them access to old versions of the
software. And so yeah, Agenda's way of
doing that was I I don't actually know
anybody there, so I don't know
technically, you know, how they did it,
but like they would have had to have
built a system into the app where every
single feature had to have a like year
gate on it. But then the crazy part
about that to me is just the QA. It's
like you have to be able to QA every
year's version of it. So somebody who
bought it and didn't pay for the upgrade
and had it for 10 years, you need to be
able to run it in that mode to see the
is this version that we're releasing
this year totally broken in that mode.
And I feel like every single year that
would just get more and more and more
complicated, right?
>> Yeah. I mean, I found a blog post about
it from seven years ago. So yeah, gosh,
time flies. But yeah, it looks like
they're still doing it.
>> I should get them on the show because
that would be very interesting to talk
to.
>> I think the developer was someone that
was pretty like he had a presence on
Twitter and then I think the great, you
know, social media divide happened and I
I don't know, maybe that was he's on
Mastadon or somewhere, but Drew, I think
his name was his name. But yeah, I
always thought that model was really it
it felt sustainable, but it felt
technically like the implementation of
it would be difficult to do.
>> I feel like the implementation's pretty
straightforward. It's the QA that's hard
because I'm essentially doing the same
thing in Frameus, but it's not
complicated because it's just the
content that changes. So, it's like if I
release a new feature, it's like you'll
have the new feature, you just might not
be able to use it with a current frame
or whatever like that. Yeah. So, testing
wise, it doesn't really matter. It's not
like I need to test every single piece
of content that my app can show. But, if
you're doing it around features, it's
like I just feel like it would get
really complicated. But, I'm sure they
If they've been doing it for this long,
I'm sure they have all sorts of
interesting ways to deal with all those.
>> I think uh when I when I Googled it is a
is a perfect time to talk about the the
great press power of Charlie Chapman
that I constantly always uh give you
half half joking uh digs about on on
when we chat throughout the year because
I I try to get press all the time and it
never works. But I just Googled Framus
and man we got Max stories tech crunch 9
to5 max six colors daring fireball like
you you just crushed the press game.
>> That was my first uh uh fireball which
that
>> was it your first one. For some reason I
thought there was another one but yeah.
Yeah. I'm the only loser in our friends
that that hasn't been fire balled. So
John, if you're listening come on man
hook me up. It's funny like your app
portfolio is almost like the iOS power
user guide. like if if if Apple was to
do like a you'll love these like power
apps by any developers like almost all
of yours could fit in that you know dark
toys and and Framus and and all those
things.
>> It's luck that I kind of landed in it to
a degree in a lot of different ways but
also like when I joined an iOS team for
the very first time and I' I'd been
doing web development and I was like I
need a side project and I need to build
an app uh or else I'm not going to be
helpful on this team. I have a list of
app ideas because I'm a nerd and picked
this one because it doesn't have a
backend. The very first thing I did
wasn't start coding, which was
>> I love that. That's usually our starting
point. Do we have to deal with the back
end? Nope. Let's build.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Well, and in my
case, it was because I I was doing
backend development. It's like, I don't
want to spend time doing the thing I
already know how to do. The first thing
I did was I wrote down, all right, I'm
going to treat this like a product.
Like, cuz I want to wear this hat. This
is really fun. And I I was like, I need
three guiding principles for why this
exists because there's a million white
noise apps out there. And I could
actually I'm just going to pull it up
because we can do that. All right. So,
this is literally the first doc last
updated August 4th, 2019. So, apparently
I moved off of this doc into something
else. So, yeah, this is truly the
original the original words. So, I
actually had three and here's what they
are. So the first one is
configurability, targeting pro users who
want to use as many options and hooks to
work the app into their workflow as
possible. So that was literally the
first thing cuz that was what I felt
like was the least served and it was an
area I knew. So if you're asking why do
I get press among that crowd? Well, that
was literally my guiding principle
number one when I built it. The next
thing is speed, which is kind of the
same thing like open the app and playing
a sound should be as fast as possible
>> but still really speaks to that same
demographic though.
>> That's what I mean. Yeah. Yeah, cuz what
do they hate? Electron apps, you know,
something slow, something not efficient.
You know,
>> that's why I didn't have onboarding at
first, which I should change, but like
the idea was it should get you to a
sound as fast as possible. When you
first open the app, you don't even see
other sounds. You literally see a big
play button, and that was like part of
my, you know, overly thinking it idea.
>> I think that's part of the part of the
it strengths. Honestly,
>> I don't disagree. I should try it
because I, you know, it's one of those
things where it's like if it helps with
conversion, yeah,
>> it's worth and as I've added more
features behind the scenes, like I still
get emails about adding the ability to
create mixes, which is a feature I've
had in there for like three years.
>> It's like if I had a simple you can mix
sounds here, uh, then people might hit
the button that literally is on the main
page to create a mix.
>> Tip kit that bad boy, man. Throw throw
one in.
>> Or or I tip kit it. That's true. That's
true. So yeah, speed was the second one.
And then the third one was keep it dark
parenthesis expect fat fingers. That's
where the the name dark noise comes from
is like the apps that me and my wife
were using were bright and when you use
it at night it was annoying. And I wear
glasses and that's why I said expect fat
fingers. My the very first design, which
is really really ugly, was literally
like a circle that it was as wide as the
screen was because the idea was it
should just be the easiest thing to hit
in the world. And then I for looks
reasons I shrunk it, but then I made it
white and everything else is very very
black and dark. Kind of like the alarm,
you know, the alarm has the big orange,
you know, snooze or whatever. I think
that's a big part of the press thing. I
you know there's a lot of things I I do
obviously to try and make that work but
a big part of it is because it's it's
aimed squarely at that group and what
came along with the target pro users
that wasn't part of my original thinking
but immediately like a couple months
after releasing because iOS 13 came out
like a month after I released it. I
learned very quickly aiming for prousers
means implementing whatever features
Apple gives you right away, which was
fine by me because I was one of those
dorks who like was into it and wanted to
do all that. But that also makes people
I say it makes Apple very happy, but
Apple is obviously a big cloud of lots
of people. So that's people on App Store
editorial are hunting around for apps
that utilize their new frameworks.
engineers inside of the spaceship are
hunting around for apps that utilize
their features because they're testing,
did we break this? Did we mess this up?
>> And if they find an app that, you know,
a lot of the standard apps that you you
hear about or whatever, it's like they
listen to a lot of the same podcasts,
uh, not all of them do, but a lot of
them do. And like those apps that always
take advantage of the latest features,
those are going to be the easiest apps
for them to test out and see like, did I
break this? Does this run on Vision Pro?
Whenever Vision Pro auto will run your
iPad app, they're going to use the usual
suspects as well as obviously the
YouTubes and the Netflixes and the big
apps that everybody uses. But if they're
trying to test like, did my esoteric
widget feature,
>> does that work over here? Well, they're
going to go to one of the indie apps
that they know implemented it. Those are
the things that have really helped on on
sort of that press. It's funny because
uh I' I've almost like part of me is
like man I just give up like on press
but it's so it can be so powerful and
like I know I'm skipping ahead here but
like when it came to Alex that was the
one where I was like I think this one
can do it you know for a lot of reasons
because you know it's like that power
user app it it's built all around iOS
features and you know I don't want to
give away names but like I had a few
people in Apple using it like throughout
the summer like you know engineer uh a
few in human interface and the app store
editorial team. So, I'm like, "This is
it." Like, the stars are going to align.
And then when the launch day came out,
and actually I feel like press was kind
of weird with this cycle. Like, there
wasn't there the usual like here are the
apps for iOS 26, which I feel like that
wasn't day and day. Like, didn't that
happen like a week or so after?
>> No, most of them never happened at all.
Talking about the press, not Apple.
>> Like the press, there's usually because
there was always like every year there
was that kind of article on all the big
sites. definitely took a hit across all
of them. I think Techrunch eventually
did and 9 to5 like a month later or
something did, but it was way less
impactful.
>> Yeah, it was all about liquid glass.
>> I was surprised. I really expected this
year and you know this is the the other
side to the coin of what I just said is
I don't know what the right phrase is.
You're throwing your lot in with
something you can't really control,
right? And that is a risk. And this year
was an example of that because like I
thought for sure that there would be a
big focus on like who's using the Apple
Foundation models in interesting ways.
>> Dude, I totally forgot that even came
out.
>> Yeah. And it was like the press didn't
lean into it. But honestly, Apple didn't
really lean that hard into it if I
remember correctly.
>> Yeah. I don't remember like a bunch of
lists about it, which is this year I
felt like was massive. There was so many
things that you could angle an app
launch towards that yeah I don't know I
feel like this was a year I felt like I
lucked out because this was a good year
to release a new app because there was
so much you could show off like new
stuff with appetentence foundation
models the new design language like all
these things and I don't know I guess
one thing in retrospect that may have
happened was the launch was so big for
Apple that I think the focus was just on
Apple's ecosystem at large instead of
like the third party apps that we're
building for him.
>> Yeah, that's true. Let's talk about
Alex. So, I talked about the app that I
released. Um, but yeah, you've released
I think two really briefly Elite
Football, which is your soccer app.
>> That was last year.
>> Oh, that was last year. It's been out
for a bit. Yeah.
>> And I know that's not like a huge app
for you, so we we don't have to get into
the details on that. Yeah, you released
uh Alex, which to me felt like, this
isn't the disc on Elite Hoops because
Elite Hoops is like a capital A app
still, but Alex felt like a return to
form in the sense of like this is a, you
know, Jordan Morgan TM app. Like it felt
like a U app in that sense. Uh not as
big of a market, not as big of a
business. and you knew that going in and
that was not uh your thinking, but it
was an app that scratched the n itch,
which I'll let you explain what it
actually does, but importantly, it just
felt like you. It had that level of like
delight and polish and all that stuff
that that I think of as a Jordan Morgan
app. And that was really fun to watch.
But yeah, what's the story behind behind
that? Like where did that come from?
>> You nailed it. Like I ever since Spinac,
cuz Spinac was a lot like that. like,
you know, it was more like polish and
form over the actual function of like
what problem does it solve, who is it
for? Um, but it's pretty. I wanted to
have that again cuz like you're right,
Elite Hoops I think of much more as a
business. Like
>> I integrate new iOS features cuz I can't
help myself and I always will. And one
that I was really proud of actually last
year was like the custom like pencil
kit. like you can you can customize the
toolbar and I added like all the elite
hoops like glyphs of that coaches use to
draw plays like squiggly arrows and you
know boxes all this stuff and like it
had the custom haptics so like I still
do stuff for it but Alex was just like I
want another spin stack that that's what
it was like I don't really care if it
makes tons of money it'll be nice if it
can but like I'm at least unlike spin
stack I'm at least going to have like a
very clear market for it and like who
would use it and why they would use it.
So, all that to say, I'm I annoyingly
track so much data about my life to
where it's it's getting to the point
where it even annoys me. Like sleep, I
track my food, I track water intake.
I've tracked my food almost like ever
since Apple Health came out. Like
whenever
>> What do you use for that?
>> Uh I use food noms. And I joked with uh
Ryan for a long time when I'd seen him
at Deep Dish Swift. I'm like, I'm still
not a pro user, dude. Like you give way
too much for free. Like I don't like you
got to do something. And then he finally
all the new all the new AI uh like input
stuff.
>> He finally got me last year. And it was
funny because it was like a fun moment
for him, you know, and he's doing really
well with food noms, but I was like this
is the year, man. Like I I finally
converted. So that's a good lesson in
product development at at large. Like he
needs to get on here, man. He's got a
great story.
>> Well, no, he's been on the show quite a
while ago. Yeah. The show's getting old
enough now. I used to have a rule that
the only person who's ever allowed to
return is you. And it was kind of a
running joke.
>> The famed Christmas special.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. I already broke
that once I started, you know, Revenue
Cats already tearing down all the, you
know, foundations of the show, but the
the launch episode was our live episode
we did at uh at our conference.
>> Oh, yeah. So, he's been on twice
technically then.
>> Yeah. With uh uh Ryan Jones with
Flighty. And it was really fun. Even
though that episode was great, like
legitimately.
>> It was. Yeah.
>> It was very fun.
>> But it was also like God, I wish I had
another hour. Like
>> it was death to to only have 30 minutes.
But that was a good signal to me that
like I can have on people who I've had
on before.
>> You need both the Ryan's back. Actually,
you need you need to get Ryan Jones back
and uh and and
>> Well, but Ryan Jones Oh, you mean like
do a normal episode with them?
>> Just a Yeah, I mean Flighty is an
interesting one cuz it launched the same
time that Spinstack did, but it's been
around and
>> as did Food Noms as did uh Dark Knight.
>> Did Food Noms launch around that same
time?
>> I believe it was 2019. Yeah, it may have
been 2020, but it was in that same we've
talked about it. There was a post swift
UI like boom. And it's ironic because I
don't think any of the apps we just
labeled our Swift UI apps,
>> right?
>> But it was right around the time that
Swift UI came out. And maybe it's really
more attributed to Swift like matured by
that point. I I don't know the details
cuz my story has nothing to do with the
lay of the land. I I don't think. But it
feels like there was this boom in from
like 20 maybe 2018 2019 through
2020 2021. Like it didn't feel like it
died with the pandemic, but there was
all these like indie apps. When I
started the show, it felt like there was
just constantly these new apps coming
out and everybody was referring to it as
like a resurgence cuz there had been
this lull for a while. And I feel like
we're back in one of those lulls lately.
>> I was just about to say that same thing.
And I don't know if it's because of it's
our jobs, like we're so focused on
helping people grow revenue, but like my
whole feed is is like growth hacking.
Like if you ask me to to just list like,
hey, what's that indie app that just
came out recently? Like I don't have one
off off the top of my head. You know,
here's my theory because I've thought a
lot about this. Uh and it's actually one
of the reasons why I was very excited to
try and get the show back going again. I
think that in whatever year it was,
2022, 2023, whenever Twitter became
untwittered,
>> and all that drama happened, there was a
big lift and move away from the internet
of a significant portion of the
legacy of craftsmanship,
app developer, influencer type people. A
lot of them went to Masttodon, but then
once they got there, you know, it's it's
an interesting platform and I'm a
supporter, yada yada, but like it's not
a place where uh you find new people and
new voices and it doesn't really foster
this sort of growing community.
>> It's a place where people go and hang
out with some of their friends to a
degree, but it's very different.
>> It was almost just like a specific type
of influencer group, which is the I
don't know how you describe it. It's not
just indie app developers. It's
specifically like the legacy of the old
delicious Mac app generation. you can
draw a straight line and you can you can
find people and connect these dots, you
know, through through tap bots and uh
like all these people who went
transitioned into iOS and did really
really well and I think that connected
to that group that we're talking about
in 2019 2018 and like there's this kind
of continuity of people and then in this
one moment like it was decapitated
and there was nobody there and so if
you're coming out of college and you're
wanting to make
There's two factors that are true. You
you got a job at a company, but you're
wanting to do stuff on your own or
whatever, and you're on on Twitter
because that's the platform where you go
if you want to like find people in in
our space. The people you're going to
see are either going to be all AI
oriented, which is where all the sort of
exciting action is happening. But that's
happened before with web. So, that's not
new. But then uh on the app developer
side, there isn't anybody on this sort
of craftsmanship thing advocating for
that anymore. It's pretty much all I
don't want to say all like vibe coders
because that's not really true, but it's
people who are talking about their MR or
how they've yeah
>> ran these big influencer campaigns and
put, you know, I put $30,000 into this
thing and I got $100,000 out like and
I'm not I'm not saying those are bad,
but it's very different. You know, it's
funny because like as you were saying
that I realized that it's almost like
that with me more personally, too. Like
I don't talk as much anymore about like,
hey, here's this new API
>> cuz it doesn't feel like that's the
conversation.
>> Yeah. And it I know we've reminisced
about this before, probably on one of
the previous Christmas specials, but
like the time back when like NS Hipster
had a new post every week or you had
just like good friends like you know
Becky from Yarn Buddy, I don't think she
really is on social as much anymore. or
they were just like all these internet
friends that were all in the same spot
for a short period of time and it was
those were the like those were the days
you know there's still people doing it
like Clemen Strasser he's one who I see
>> very actively talking on social media
and posting about things he's doing
things he's trying you know and and sort
of pushing the medium now his is more
game oriented
>> sure
>> um but I feel like he's doing that I
feel like uh Andy Allen who if you're
listening, Andy, I would love to have
you on the show. He's definitely
somebody who is still actively
constantly talking about the craft of
iOS development, you know what I mean? I
only say that to say that that it does
still exist. It's not just completely
moved into the the business side. And
it's funny because I feel like the
majority of my time running this show, I
would have all these conversations and
talk to people who were like, I was
embarrassed to to care about the
business or to try subscriptions or to
try this. And it was all about trying to
get people to be a little more open to
the idea of like it's okay to not let
your business die and to actually like
treat it like a business and not just as
a piece of art. And then all this it was
like it violently switched to now I'm
like whoa like I love the business
obviously I work for both of us we work
for companies that are all about making
money and and making sustainable
businesses whatever but there's a little
bit of a like but software is cool too
like let's make cool crafted you know
well well done things. One of the things
that doing this podcast has helped
already with in the recordings I've been
doing, you know, I've done maybe five or
six of these recordings at this point is
I come out of them and I'm just like,
people make cool stuff. Like
>> it feels good to talk about that again.
Not because the other stuff is bad, but
because I think I at least was getting a
little over oversaturated with uh just
the like money money side. And so I
yeah, I definitely think there's there's
a balance there. But anyway, very long
aside to say, you apparently agreed
because you wanted to make an app that
was about the craftsmanship side. And
so, yeah, what is that app? Okay, so
after our 30 minute aside, it's a
caffeine tracker. Someone has been
waiting 30 minutes to just be like, what
is the app? What does it do? So, yeah. I
mean, we were chatting about this before
you started recording, but you know,
we're both coffee drinkers. Um, and like
I said, I I track so much data about my
life because I just think it's nerdy and
fun and interesting. I've always tracked
caffeine and I had let's see two dubdubs
ago when uh Luca Bernardi he did a
session over like the interactive
widgets and he
>> oh and it was it was a caffeine
tracking widget. Yeah, I
>> forgot it was and I was like that's
perfect. Like I I use a shortcut all the
time. Like this is the use case. And so,
you know, Elite Hoops had been out for a
couple months by that point and I was
like, "Ah, this is a great time to like
do a spin stacky project where I'm not
going to really worry too much about the
revenue. I'm just going to make sure
there's a there's a defined target thing
that it does and just kind of go off the
rails." So, I had like the loose design
of it done over that summer just for
kicks and giggles. And it just sat on my
phone for years unchanged and I used it
all the time.
>> This is not a unique thing for Jordan.
>> No,
>> I feel like Jordan randomly pulls out
like a screenshot and we're like, "Whoa,
what app is that?" And he's like, "Oh,
yeah. This is a little app I built for
myself, you know, a long time, like an
entire to-do app or something.
>> Side quests. I go on a lot of side
quests." Um, you know, and sometimes
they're useful, sometimes not so much.
But I didn't have like the app done.
Like if you opened the app, it was
pretty much like placeholder stuff. Like
I had like
>> You were just dumping it into Healthit.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's just And that's one of
the great things about the app is I
don't own the data model which is a
which is great for me because it just
goes to Health Kit. Like it it's all
through Health Kit. So yeah, I would use
the widget and I would use the shortcut
to just log the same things like
espresso. I I'm I'm so boring. I drink
like the same coffees all the time. But
I don't even remember what like pushed
me over the edge to do it. Like I don't
know if this was like a I know over the
years I've brought up the group chat,
you know, like we we've we've chatted
for years and I don't know if like and
and you guys are my indie like
throughine if if one of you finally just
convinced me to like make it into an app
or or how it happened. Like
>> I don't remember.
>> I don't either.
>> It's probably the shipon that
>> that's what it was. That that'd be
ironic. And this year I was just like
I'm going to do it like I'm I'm very
nerdy with like lists and goals. Like I
have a reminder to make my goals for
next year I saw coming up in like a
week. Don't you have an app for that
too? Am I remembering that correctly?
>> I did. I finally sunset that one. But
you know, the blog post for that was
like very popular like a lot. And you
know, people always say like, "Oh, ship
it." But you never know like, you know,
if they're actually going to use it. It
was very like, yeah, everyone wants the
mockup, you know. But my goal for this
year, like I'm looking at my indie
goals, and it was to ship I've always
wanted to ship a new app with a new
version of iOS because I had never done
that. So that was like my goal this year
is like I'm not going to really worry
about Elite Hoops and iOS 26. Like I
want it to look good. I want it to work,
but I'm not going to worry about like as
long as it works with liquid glass
>> because that audience doesn't
>> No, they don't care.
>> They're already going to be upset that
the OS changed.
>> Exactly. Like their why is this all
bubbly and soapy now? So, and it was a
crazy summer and it it was actually one
of the most fun times I've had building
and I really needed that cuz like that
joy of building I just hadn't had in a
while. And I spent that whole summer
just going nuts on it. And it was crazy
because with the advent of like AI uh
assistants, I could just build out I got
to a point where I had Claude code
almost perfectly make an app intent for
me. Like cuz I I made like how I wanted
it and I had my patterns and I had like
the entities. I had just the way I
wanted it all in one file. And then from
there I could pretty much just dream up
what shortcut I wanted to make or what
action I wanted. and cloud code could
could do it almost perfectly the first
time. So I ended up having like I don't
know I think there's like 50 to 70 app
intents in the app. It's an interesting
side effect. This is a little technical
but they they changed the app intense
what two years ago
>> from this kind of insane like UI
thing where and it was it was not saved
in a plain text file. it was in some
sort of XML or something weird format
and they changed it to code and
obviously at that time they I'm almost
sure certain that the reason they did
that was not because of AI coding tools
becoming popular but they very quickly
became popular and I guess now that
actually would make that way easier to
do. It is because like the the API is
like simple to get started with but kind
of hard to master. But I just like I
found the sweet spot with Claude where
it could just spit them out. And so I
went crazy with that and then I I had so
many powerful shortcuts. Like I was
having so much fun with it. Like I would
just think up something like I don't
know when's like caffeine going to be
out of my body and like how many shots
of espresso is that equivalent to? just
crazy stuff like you know I'm like why
not it takes me like 5 minutes cuz now I
have the baseline down and I had already
written like the plumbing for it years
ago like the health kit stuff to
retrieve the data so like the hard
critical paths were already finished.
Yeah. I mean the whole point of the app
was I wanted that nice pretty indie app.
That's what I wanted to make. And if we
link to the press kit, like if you go to
alexcaffracker.com
and look at presskit at the top, like
you'll see all of the iOS ccentric
features that I shipped for it. And it's
just like and I marketed it that way.
I'm like this is like a iOS playground
for caffeine tracking and it turned out
really fun. I'm really proud of it. Like
I think it's one of the prettiest apps
that I've made. And it's funny because
one of the the biggest compliments it
gets is the onboarding. Like I'm like,
"Yeah, but do you like like the app?"
you know, but just everything like
there's visual lookup, you can scan to
log drinks, there's the interactive
shortcuts, it has the foundation models,
all of the liquid glass stuff, alarm
kit, widgets. So like I I hit every
single box that I could. It was on
purpose cuz like I wanted to make an
insanely good iOS app that shows all the
features and it was playful and that was
like really like freeing for me because
Elite Hoops is more like
>> they have a job to get done. They don't
really want like the nice cool
animation. Whereas from the start, like
I came up with the idea to have Alex be
a mascot a long time ago. I could just
kind of riff on that and just be goofy
and sarcastic in a lot of places. And I
forget one big inspiration for the
design was at the time, remember two
years ago, photos went through that big
redesign where they kind of went all in
on this single long scrolling content
view where they kind of shifted away
from tab views, which that's that's
since reversed. But I I liked the idea
on a smaller scale. I was like, "What if
I can make Alex just be like one just
sheet of stuff about caffeine?" Like
there's no toggling tabs. There's no
other places to go. Like it's just one
view and everything is there.
>> And so that's where I ended up. And uh
it it turned out really nice. It turned
out really pretty and it's always going
to be my little thing to tinker with
every summer. Yeah. It's my muse.
Absolutely. And again, I'm I'm really
thankful that Elite Hoops is growing and
is like doing stable growth, you know,
whatever you want to call it, because
like it gives me an excuse to have this
little thing to just kind of play around
with. Um, now don't get me wrong, I
would love for it to grow and make as
much as as Elite Hoops does. And I think
there's paths to get there. And a little
like realization that I had is when I
was looking into this genre of health
apps, I think, I can't prove this. I
think what's happening is if you go to
the health app and you look at some sort
of metric like uh water intake and you
scroll down or weight or uh steps, it'll
say recommended apps and it'll list like
four or five third party apps. So if you
look at weight, you'll see uh happy
scales on there. Uh if you look at step
counts, pedometer plus is on there. If
you look at water intake, water minders
on there, water llama's on there. And in
my head, I'm like, "Dude, these have to
be driving
crazy amounts of downloads because so
many people look at the health app." And
my hope is that eventually they'll do
the same thing for caffeine. And I was
shocked.
>> So, Caffeine doesn't have one right now.
>> Caffeine has no like use these apps to
track your caffeine.
>> Oh my gosh. It would be so cool if you
suddenly saw a stream of users. I wonder
if they surely they must expose that in
App Store Connect. I don't know. And
I've even tried to get businessy. Uh,
let me put my suit and tie on. I got on
LinkedIn and like tried to find like
Health Kit engineers or like anyone that
worked at HealthKit. And I don't think
anyone like accepted my request cuz it's
LinkedIn and they're like, who is this
weirdo, you know? But I'm just like,
guys, if anyone like you should put
caffeine apps in cuz I'm not the only
one. Uh there's uh High Coffee has been
around for several years. It's a great
app. It has like a lot more like
>> knobs and stuff you can turn than Alex
does. Um, and then there's a few other
ones. And then water minder actually and
water llama. They both allow you to to
put caffeine. It's not the sole focus.
Water intake obviously is. So that's
kind of my pie in the sky wish. Like if
the health app does that, like this
thing could really
>> grow quick and for uh air quotes for
free because it's like the health app is
on every iPhone. Obviously, Elite Hoops
has a much clearer clear clearer like
TAM. You know, you know, you can target
coaches and that coaches are going to be
willing to spend because it like
>> saves on their time for their job. It's
like a it's a tool.
>> This feels like way more kind of like
more like dark noise in the sense that
it's way more just ubiquitous. It is.
It's still a lot less than I guess like
a white noise app or something like a
smaller percentage of users would use
it. But it's like it's very widely
applicable. Like it feels like the type
of thing that
you know if you handed it to one of
these people that knows how to play the
influencer campaign game, they could go
out and find
health influencer people who are already
recommending people track their caffeine
cuz there's got to be just massive
markets of people that do that and like,
hey, like maybe recommend this app as a
as a nice one or run some sort of deal
or something with them. Like it does
feel like there's a a little bit more,
you know, consumer app playbooks that
you could run with this than Elite
Hoops, which is it's not it's obviously
not B to C, but it's almost more like
that. It's much more a consumer app than
Elite Hoops would be.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And I almost when I, you know,
contracted with EVO for this month, I
almost did it for Alex because I'm like
there's so many angles of like the UGC
uh playbook that you could run with it.
Uh but I was like, ah, I'm I'm just
going to be a big boy and, you know,
focus on Le Hoops.
>> Well, and in reality, like the the value
and the amount people were willing to
spend is going to be very different
between those two. I mean, I guess cheap
is very very subjective to whoever
you're talking to, but like for this to
make significant money for me, it would
be a volume thing. Like the the
downloads would have to be extremely
high. And it may never be, but the other
angle to this is like the prestige play,
too. Like, you know, of course,
everybody wants like a Apple design
award recognition with Apple. So, it's
like this is almost like my Apple reward
bait app, too. Like, if one was going to
get any recognition, like it would be
this one. the sports like coach oriented
this changes my actual life apps, they
often win stuff because design the
design award is just as much about
innovation in some capacity as it is
about uh you know it looking beautiful
or whatever.
>> For sure. For sure. It really is. I'm
glad that it's out because like I I get
I kind of have my cake and eat it too
now. Like if I just want to do like fun
pretty iOS stuff then I'll open up Alex
and you know it doesn't even support the
last version of iOS. Like I didn't even
bother with iOS 18. It's just like this
is for iOS 26. I'm building it for iOS
26. Like
>> I'm just going all in on it. And when we
were laughing about the press stuff
earlier, like uh Apple, they they did
ask for the promo art and I was really
like psyched about that. But remember, I
think this is on the the archives, too.
When they asked for the promo art for
Spinstack, they didn't use it for a full
calendar year. So it's like they haven't
used it as of this recording that I know
of. I mean, I have app figures and you
know, they ping you now from App Store
Connect like too. I think be like a
major feature.
>> So, it hasn't been used that I know of,
but like it's the promo art is so
bananas that like if it gets used, I'm
going to be I'm going to be so excited.
Like, yeah, I think I sent it to you.
It's like I had a designer just like go
nuts with all like the little Alex
glyphs and like it had Siri orb glow. It
was like, you know, like pulsing through
the top of the espresso cup. So, it it
was wild. Maybe they saw it and they're
like, "Yeah, we're not using that." So,
so we'll see. So, like the goals are
like make a pretty app and you know,
it's it's the app I use most on my
phone. So, that's kind of like a fun fun
thing. I'll never get tired of working
on it. And I have a laundry list of
ideas like like we all do for the stuff
that we make.
>> But, yeah, I mean, it's out. I'm proud
that it's out. It was a it was just a
personal like achievement. Like, I just
want to ship with a new version of iOS.
I've never done it. Um, so I can mark
that off the list. It's been done and
you know, I'll I'll soup it up every
year for sure. Awesome. Well, I think
we're we're getting uh short on time, so
I guess we should we should probably go
ahead and wrap this up. Another another
year in the books, as they say. It was
super fun doing this. It's always super
fun doing this. I'm glad uh launched
survived cuz, you know, this is the only
time we're allowed to talk.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. We we were born bound
by our contracts at both jobs to not
speak formally outside outside of these
walls.
>> Exactly. No, this is great. So, I guess
uh where can people find you and uh I
guess your work? No, I'm just kidding.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Uh XJordan Morgan or
my blog swiftc.com.
And I I think I list all the apps out on
there too if you ever want to check them
out. So, I am actually unlike blessed by
the ASO god. So, if you search for Alex
or you search for Elite Hoops, you'll
you'll find them up there pretty high.
RIP for Frammus and it's ASO.
>> Yeah, it's all good. It's all good. But,
you know, if you're listening and you
haven't you haven't downloaded it yet,
you should go search frame scroll scroll
scroll
>> find it. Download it
>> or look at any of the 10 major press
outlets that have covered it as well.
>> Yeah. Yeah. There you go. There you go.
>> Thank you so much for listening. You can
find more launched at launchedfm.com
and you can find me on pretty much all
the social medias. I'm @_chucky on
Twitter or charliemchapman pretty much
everywhere else. And of course, huge
thanks to Revenue for making this
episode and all future episodes of
launched possible. I'll see you all
again in 2 weeks.